# Saim Akhtar

### **Backend Developer**

A programming enthusiast having distinctive competencies in Node.js and Python Development, backend servers development, scripting, docker, CI/CD, cloud Services and Databases with 3+ years of experience. Strong communication skills with experience on working with remote, resource and project based models with clients. Loves doing open source contributions and learning latest trends in tech world

Cell: 0313-2985810

Email: <u>saimakhtar98@gmail.com</u>
Github: <u>https://github.com/Saim-Akhtar</u>

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/saim-akhtar-060130179/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/saim-akhtar-060130179/</a>

**Upwork**: <a href="https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/">https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/</a> ~019bf7f118a9c45d71/

# **Professional Experience**

November 2020 - Present

KoderLabs, Karachi - Associate Software Engineer

- Working on backend servers and apis with nest js and flask
- Agile based development

November 2019 - May 2020

#### **Virtuosoft, Karachi** - Devops Intern

- Building and working with Docker Images and containers
- Re-factoring cloud functions in Node JS and Python
- Writing Python and Bash Scripts for automation
- Working on Google Cloud Platform and cloud services
- Creating dags and automated pipelines in Airflow
- Building automated pipeline with github repositories

May 2019 - Present

### **Upwork** - Freelance developer

- Developing web apps and backend servers
- Web Scraping, data cleaning and filtering
- Cloud services
- Dockerizing applications
- Automation
- Bug fixing in scripts and testing

• Teaching and guiding as an Instructor

February 2019 - October 2019

#### **Softious Systems, Karachi** - JavaScript Developer

- Developing REST APIs using Node JS, Express, MongoDB
- Token Based Authentication, both local and Social OAUTH, using Passport Js and JWT
- TDD (Test Driven Development) using Mocha, Chai
- Developing Web apps using Firebase
- Deployment on Heroku

# **Projects**

### Devhub

- 1. A developer hub where the github users can chat with each other and view other others work, like and comment on different repositories
- 2. Front end developed using React & Redux
- 3. Backend end developed using Nodejs, express & MongoDB as a database
- 4. Chat module implemented using Socket.io

### **Digital Marketplace**

- 1. A digital marketplace developed using Django
- 2. Admin will store the books and relevant chapters
- 3. Users can register and purchase the books they need
- 4. Payment method implemented using Stripe Api
- 5. Deployed on Azure and dockerized using docker-compose

#### Node-OLX

- 1. An olx like ecommerce website developed using Nodejs, Expressjs, MongoDB
- 2. Authentication applied using JWT and Passport js
- 3. OAuth Login with Google

## **Distributed System**

- A distributed database system implemented using Nodejs, Sequelize, MySQL
- 2. A master-slave distributed architecture followed

## **Automating Linkedin**

- 1. A client's project where his linkedin connections are fetched, profile details extracted and saved in google sheets
- 2. Worked with 1 more team member
- 3. Automated linkedin search
- 4. Project implemented using Python, Selenium, Pandas, Numpy

### **Private Client Project**

- 1. A client's private project about entrepreneur network
- 2. Developed using Django
- 3. Worked with 1 more team member

## **Skills**

### **Programming & Scripting:**

- JavaScript (ES6)
- > Python
- > C++/C
- ➤ Bash Scripting

#### **Backend Development:**

- ➤ Nodejs/Expressis
- Django/Django Rest Framework
- ➤ GraphQL
- ➤ Rest APIs
- ➤ Socket.io
- > Serverless structures

#### Databases:

- MongoDB (Mongoose)
- ➤ NoSQL
- ➤ MySQL
- ➤ Postgresql
- ➤ Oracle Database

### Data Scraping & Analysis Libraries:

➤ Numpy

- > Pandas
- > Selenium
- ➤ Beautiful soup
- ➤ Requests

#### **Devops Tools & Clouds:**

- > Docker
- > Airflow
- Google cloud platform
- > Firebase, Azure & Heroku deployments

## **Education**

- □ NED University of Engineering & Technology, Karachi Bachelors of Computer Science & Information Technology . 2017-Progress
- □ All Pakistan Memon Federation
   Web and Mobile Application Development . 2018 2019
- □ Bahria College NORE 1Intermediate in Engineering . 2015-1017
- PAF Base Masroor Matriculation . 2013-2015

# **Udemy Course**

Created a course for client as Instructor for Complete ES6 JavaScript: https://www.udemy.com/course/javascript-es6-for-beginners/